Edwin B. Rollins Papers MS054
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Edwin B. Rollins Papers
1902 -- 1976
1850 -- 1976
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Rollins, Edwin B.
MS054
3.4 Linear Feet 2 Hollinger boxes and 15 photograph boxes of various sizes. Most of the collection is housed as part of the University Photographs collection and take up portions of those photograph boxes.
565 Digital Object(s)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series: Notebooks; Writings; and Photographs.
Biographical / Historical
Edwin B. Rollins (1878-1980), E1901, was professor of electrical engineering, chair of the department and acting dean of the College of Engineering. In addition he pursued his interests in photography and research into the history of the built environment of the Medford campus.
Rollins was born in Lewiston, Maine, on June 1, 1878. He attended Tufts College and graduated in 1901. While an undergraduate Rollins worked on campus assisting with the new electrical system on the campus, winding transformers and installing lights. He earned fifteen cents per hour for the labor. Upon graduation, Rollins joined Tufts' engineering faculty as an instructor of physics and electrical engineering. He became assistant professor in 1910 and in 1928 was made full professor and chairman of the department of electrical engineering at Tufts. He served as acting dean of the engineering school from 1927 to 1929. In 1948 he received the alumni association's Distinguished Service Award.
Over the years, Rollins, in addition to his academic and administrative activities, built a full-scale model telephone office, a collection of lamps, wrote a history of the first forty years of electrical engineering at Tufts, and compiled in notebooks a history of buildings and gates on the Medford campus.
Rollins worked closely with Professor Melville Munro who, on the side, worked as campus photographer for three decades. Rollins, only a few years Munro's senior, sparked Munro's interest in photography, encouraging him to embark on what was to become an exhaustive photographic history of Tufts covering the entirety of Munro's years at Tufts. Rollins assisted Munro in assembling the scrapbooks and taking photographs.
For most of his years at Tufts, Rollins lived at 84 Packard Avenue, with his wife, Mabel. He died in Rockland, Maine, on December 17, 1980, at the age of 102.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains notebooks created by Rollins to document the changes in the built environment of Tufts' Medford campus from 1854 to the mid-twentieth century.
University history; College of Engineering; Dept. of Electrical Engineering; Medford Campus; Faculty
- Notebooks, 1940 -- 1955; MS054.001; 1.0 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains notebooks compiled by Rollins on the history of Tufts buildings, campus homes, the growth of the Medford campus, copies of deeds, and reminiscences of the early years of Tufts. Most contain a narrative of the topic, with photographs, and transcriptions of the original sources where Rollins did his research. The books are not dated, but the bulk of the work was completed by 1955. Some notebooks contain notes added after 1955.
  Part 2 of the Tufts Campus series is not present. The book entitled Campus Deeds is a photocopy.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged as found.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - The earlier buildings of Tufts College, 1940 -- 1955; MS054.001.001.00001; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_94a709e50214e0bb2f1e87c748a11a4f)
  - Middle group of Tufts buildings, 1940 -- 1955; MS054.001.001.00002; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_94a709e50214e0bb2f1e87c748a11a4f)
  - Later buildings of Tufts College, 1940 -- 1955; MS054.001.001.00003; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_94a709e50214e0bb2f1e87c748a11a4f)
    History of Alumnae Hall with photographs.
  - Tufts campus, Part one, 1940 -- 1955; MS054.001.001.00004; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_94a709e50214e0bb2f1e87c748a11a4f)
  - Tufts campus, Part three, 1940 -- 1955; MS054.001.001.00005; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_94a709e50214e0bb2f1e87c748a11a4f)
  - Tufts campus, Part two, 1940 -- 1955; MS054.001.001.00006; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_94a709e50214e0bb2f1e87c748a11a4f)
  - Tufts College Data, 1940 -- 1955; MS054.001.001.00007; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_94a709e50214e0bb2f1e87c748a11a4f)
  - Campus homes, Part I (a), 1940 -- 1955; MS054.001.002.00001; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box MS054 Shared 1)
  - Campus homes, Part I (b), 1940 -- 1955; MS054.001.002.00002; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box MS054 Shared 1)
  - Campus homes, Part II, 1940 -- 1955; MS054.001.002.00003; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box MS054 Shared 1)
  - Through the years at Tufts, 1940 -- 1955; MS054.001.002.00004; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box MS054 Shared 1)
  - Reminiscences, 1940 -- 1955; MS054.001.002.00005; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box MS054 Shared 1)
  - Campus deeds, 1940 -- 1955; MS054.001.002.00006; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box MS054 Shared 1)
  - Subjects, 1940 -- 1955; MS054.001.002.00008; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box MS054 Shared 1)
- Writings, 1961 -- 1976; MS054.002; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains poems and prose reminiscences of Rollins' long career at Tufts, especially of student days. Contains a description of Class Day, and his on-campus student job.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Writings, 1961 -- 1976; MS054.002.002.00007; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box MS054 Shared 1)
- Photographs, 1850 -- 1961; 1930 -- 1955; MS054.003; 0.5 Linear Feet; 565 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains photographs and photographic reproductions made by Edwin Rollins. Most of the photos are of the Tufts Medford campus and of historical figures associated with the college.
  - Thomas A. Goddard, 1860; MS054.003.DO.00332; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_94a709e50214e0bb2f1e87c748a11a4f)
    75, Found in Rollins Notebook.
    People; Portraits; Goddard, Thomas A.
  - Oliver Dean, MS054.003.DO.00356; Unknown; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 86, Box Shared 43)
    copy negative credited to Rollins (box: "Tufts People").
    People; photographic print; copy negative; Dean, Oliver
  - Benjamin F. Tweed, 1858; MS054.003.DO.00361; Unknown; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 86, Box Shared 117)
    from RNCH1, copy negative credited to Rollins (box: "Tufts People")
    People; photographic print; copy negative; copy negative; Tweed, Benjamin Franklin
  - Capen House, 1876; MS054.003.DO.00362; Unknown (Box Shared 86)
    from RNCH1
    photographic print
  - 20 Professors Row [Lewis House], 1876; MS054.003.DO.00363; Unknown (Box Shared 86)
    Buildings; Houses; photographic print
  - Leo R. Lewis, MS054.003.DO.00364; Unknown; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 86, Box Shared 117)
    from RNCH1, copy negative credited to Rollins (box: "Tufts People").
    People; Faculty; photographic print; copy negative; Lewis, Leo R.; Tufts University
  - Shipman House [80 Professors Row], 1900; MS054.003.DO.00365; Unknown (Box Shared 86)
    Houses; Buildings; photographic print
  - W.R. Shipman, MS054.003.DO.00366; Unknown; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 86, Box Shared 117)
    People; Faculty; photographic print; copy negative; Shipman, William R.
  - Helen L. Mellen, MS054.003.DO.00386; Unknown; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 86, Box Shared 117)
    RNCH1, copy negative credited to Rollins (box: "Tufts People")
    People; Librarians; photographic print; copy negative; Mellen, Helen L.
  - East Hall, 1886; MS054.003.DO.00400; Unknown (Box Shared 86)
    in RNTB1
    Buildings; Dormitories; photographic print
  - Dean Hall, MS054.003.DO.00401; Unknown; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 86, Box Shared 117)
    in RNCB2, 3x5 copy negative credited to Rollins, box: "Slides and negatives from Prof. Rollins. Donated September 1967."
    Buildings; Dormitories; photographic print; copy negative
  - The "Dog Cart" beside Curtis Hall, MS054.003.DO.00402; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 86)
    in RNCB2.
    Food service; Buildings; photographic print
  - Commons [Curtis] Hall, 1915; MS054.003.DO.00403; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 86)
    in RNCB2
    Buildings; photographic print
  - First Jackson Gymnasium Interior, MS054.003.DO.00404; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 86)
    Buildings; Gymnasiums; photographic print
  - Yeager House, 1954; MS054.003.DO.00464; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 89)
    in RNCH2
  - East Hall, 1879; MS054.003.DO.00571; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 89, Box Shared 117)
    credited to Rollins
    Buildings; Housing; Dormitories; photographic print; copy negative
  - Tousey House, 106 Professors Row, MS054.003.DO.00681; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 54, Box Shared 42)
    Buildings; Housing; photographic print; copy negative
  - View of campus from The Rez, 1900; MS054.003.DO.00980; Unknown; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 100, Box Shared 117)
    credited to Rollins. box: "Slides and negatives from Prof. Rollins. Donated September 1967."
    Views; Reservoirs; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; photographic print; copy negative
  - Packard Hall with old barn, 1880; MS054.003.DO.01041; Unknown; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 103, Box Shared 117)
    Buildings; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; photographic print; copy negative
  - Lecture given by Daniel Pratt, 1885; MS054.003.DO.01048; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 103, Box Shared 117)
    People; photographic print; copy negative; Pratt, Daniel
  - The Bubble, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01049; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 102, Box Shared 43)
    credited to Rollins.
    photographic print; copy negative
  - Old Chemical Lab, 1930; MS054.003.DO.01054; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 103, Box Shared 117)
    box: "Slides and negatives from Prof. Rollins. Donated September 1967."
    Buildings; Academic; photographic print; copy negative; Dept. of Chemistry
  - View of campus from "The Rez" on Class Day, 1806 -- 1896; MS054.003.DO.01175; Dennison, E.B.; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 108)
    print credited to Dennison, glass plate negative credited to Rollins
    Views; glass negative
  - Physical education class, 1920; MS054.003.DO.01350; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 114, Box Shared 117)
    box: "Slides and negatives of Prof. Rollins. Donated September 1967."
    Students; People; photographic print; copy negative
  - Interior of Goddard Chapel, MS054.003.DO.01710; Unknown; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 114, Box Shared 117)
    Chapels; photographic print; copy negative
  - Robinson Hall, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01926; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
    Buildings; Academic; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - Bromfield-Pearson Building, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01927; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
  - Barnum Hall, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01928; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
  - Goddard Gymnasium, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01929; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
    Buildings; Gymnasiums; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - Curtis Hall, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01930; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
    Buildings; Administrative; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - Tufts railway station, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01931; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
    Railroad stations; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - Metcalf Hall, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01932; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
    Buildings; Dormitories; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - Tufts campus and track, 1902 -- 1912; MS054.003.DO.01933; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
    Taken at 11:30 AM, Exposure .5 seconds, Frame 8, Bright sun
    Views; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - College Hill from Broadway, 1902 -- 1912; MS054.003.DO.01934; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
    taken at 11:30am, Exposure .5 seconds, Frame 8, Bright sun
  - Goddard Chapel, 1902 -- 1912; MS054.003.DO.01935; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
    Taken at 11:30 a.m., Exposure .5 seconds, Frame 8, Bright sun
    Buildings; Chapels; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - Theta Delta Chi fraternity house, 1902 -- 1912; MS054.003.DO.01936; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
    Taken at 11:30 a.m., Exposure .5 seconds, Frame 8, Bright Sun
    Houses; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative; Theta Chi
  - College Hill, 1902 -- 1912; MS054.003.DO.01937; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
    Taken at 11:30, Exposure .5 seconds, Frame 8, Bright sun
  - College Hill from the Rez, 1902 -- 1912; MS054.003.DO.01938; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
  - Delta Tau Delta house, 1902 -- 1912; MS054.003.DO.01939; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
    Houses; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative; Delta Tau Delta
  - Delta Upsilon house, 1902 -- 1912; MS054.003.DO.01940; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
    Houses; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative; Delta Upsilon
  - MacKenzie's new building and store, 1807 -- 1896; MS054.003.DO.01941; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
    Velox 2, 8 seconds, 10 inches
    Buildings; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - Snow scene from corner of Capen and Winthrop Streets, 1802 -- 1897; MS054.003.DO.01942; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_34e5d1600919e48abf7ca3f65b427817)
    Velox #4, 4 seconds, 10 inches
  - Class of 1900 engineering students, MS054.003.DO.01943; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
    People; Students; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative; College of Engineering
  - Class of 1903 blacksmiths, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01944; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
    People; Students; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - Goddard Chapel, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01945; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
  - Bromfield Pearson Building, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01946; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
  - Paige Hall, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01947; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
  - Train station at Tufts College, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01948; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
  - Chemical lab at Tufts College, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01949; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
    Buildings; Laboratories; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - Interior of Howe Memorial Laboratory, informally referred to as The Power House, 1905; MS054.003.DO.01950; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
    Laboratories; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - View of Medford from "The Rez", 1900; MS054.003.DO.01951; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
  - View of Medford from "The Rez", 1900; MS054.003.DO.01952; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
  - Class of 1902 forging-blacksmithing class, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01953; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
  - Delta Tau Delta house or "Graves House", 1900; MS054.003.DO.01954; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c, Box Shared 117)
    Houses; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative; copy negative; Delta Tau Delta
  - Metcalf Hall, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01955; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
  - View of Medford from West Hall, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01956; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
  - East Hall, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01957; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
    Buildings; Dormitories; Academic; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - Machine shop, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01958; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
    Rooms; Academic; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - Dynamo Laboratory - Basement of Ballou, 1899; MS054.003.DO.01987; Unknown; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 28, Box Shared 117)
    Laboratories; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; photographic print; copy negative
  - View of West Medford, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01990; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
  - Goddard Chapel, 1905; MS054.003.DO.01991; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
  - Goddard Chapel with original lighting in ceiling panels that were installed in 1899, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01992; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
  - Packard Hall, 1905; MS054.003.DO.01993; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
    Buildings; Academic; Dormitories; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - View of West Somerville, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01994; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
  - View of "the Hill" from Medford, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01995; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_a525958f67b5c0ca0b8a0034972edb2c)
  - View of old railroad station and tracks, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01996; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_1952448cbc8f36afeec1e23292bfd3cc)
  - View of campus, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01997; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_1952448cbc8f36afeec1e23292bfd3cc)
  - View of Tufts Campus from Powder House, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01998; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_1952448cbc8f36afeec1e23292bfd3cc)
  - Looking north on College Avenue with the old railroad station on the left, 1900; MS054.003.DO.01999; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_1952448cbc8f36afeec1e23292bfd3cc)
  - 72 Professors Row, 1900; MS054.003.DO.02000; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_1952448cbc8f36afeec1e23292bfd3cc)
    Houses; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - Ballou Hall, 1900; MS054.003.DO.02001; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_1952448cbc8f36afeec1e23292bfd3cc)
    Buildings; Academic; Administrative; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - Barnum Hall, 1900; MS054.003.DO.02002; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_1952448cbc8f36afeec1e23292bfd3cc)
  - View south from Ballou Hall, 1900; MS054.003.DO.02003; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_1952448cbc8f36afeec1e23292bfd3cc)
  - Original Goddard Hall, 1900; MS054.003.DO.02004; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_1952448cbc8f36afeec1e23292bfd3cc)
    Buildings; Gymnasiums; Academic; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; glass negative
  - Robinson Hall, 1900; MS054.003.DO.02005; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_1952448cbc8f36afeec1e23292bfd3cc)
  - Goddard Chapel, 1900; MS054.003.DO.02006; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_1952448cbc8f36afeec1e23292bfd3cc)
  - Looking east from Paige Hall, 1900; MS054.003.DO.02007; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box data_value_missing_1952448cbc8f36afeec1e23292bfd3cc)
  - 226 College Avenue, 1950; MS054.003.DO.02025; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
    box: "Residences"
    Houses; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; copy negative
  - 11 Talbot Street, 1950; MS054.003.DO.02026; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 13 Talbot Street, 1950; MS054.003.DO.02027; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 15 Talbot Avenue, 1950; MS054.003.DO.02028; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 55 Talbot Avenue, 1950; MS054.003.DO.02029; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 61 Talbot Avenue, 1950; MS054.003.DO.02030; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 72 Professors Row, 1876; MS054.003.DO.02100; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 126 Packard Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02101; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 120 Packard Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02102; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 126 Packard Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02103; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 128 Packard Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02104; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 114 Curtis St., 1955; MS054.003.DO.02105; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 123 Packard Avenue, 1954; MS054.003.DO.02106; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 106 Professors Row, 1876; MS054.003.DO.02107; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 114 Professors Row, 1876; MS054.003.DO.02108; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 92 Professors Row, 1876; MS054.003.DO.02109; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 134 Professors Row, 1954; MS054.003.DO.02110; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 128 Professors Row, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02111; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 124 Professors Row, 1954; MS054.003.DO.02112; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 80 Professors Row, 1900; MS054.003.DO.02113; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - Tweed House, 72 Professors Row, 1857; MS054.003.DO.02114; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
    box: Residences
  - 114 Professors Row, 1954; MS054.003.DO.02115; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 106 Professors Row, 1954; MS054.003.DO.02116; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 98 Professors Row, 1954; MS054.003.DO.02117; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 98 Professors Row, 1876; MS054.003.DO.02118; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 134 Professors Row, 1876; MS054.003.DO.02119; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 65 Talbot Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02120; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 17 Latin Way, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02121; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 95 Talbot Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02122; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 97 Talbot Ave, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02123; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 101 Talbot Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02124; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 13 Sawyer Avenue, MS054.003.DO.02125; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 14 Sawyer Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02126; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 19 Sawyer Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02127; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 14 Sawyer Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02128; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 28 Sawyer Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02129; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 28 Sawyer Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02130; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 29 Sawyer Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02131; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 29)
    Houses; Edwin B. Rollins, papers; photographic print
  - 36 Sawyer Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02132; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - Sawyer Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02133; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 44 Sawyer Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02134; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 44 Sawyer Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02135; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 45 Sawyer Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02136; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 50 Sawyer Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02137; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 51 Sawyer Avenue, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02138; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 8 Professors Row, 1876; MS054.003.DO.02139; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 14 Professors Row, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02140; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 20 Professors Row, 1876; MS054.003.DO.02141; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 28 Professors Row, 1955; MS054.003.DO.02142; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
  - 38 Professors Row, 1876; MS054.003.DO.02143; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)